

AKASH JINDAL

• DETAILS •

+44-7423512047 akashjindaluk@gmail.com

LINKS

LinkedIn

SKILLS

Product Management

IT Project Management

Confluence

Agile and Scrum

Kanban

SAFE

Atlassian- JIRA

Visio

Microsoft Azure Cloud

Postman

SQL/NoSQL

User stories & Product Road Map

Lucidspark

Miro

Data Analytics - Python Pandas

Automation Testing

Git

UML

PROFILE

Professionally certified Scrum product Owner (PSPO) & certified Microsoft Azure Architect with around 6 years of experience; nominated among top 5% of consultants among 3500 applications in Infosys; 2 times awarded for dedication towards work and management of teams; GMAT 730 scorer.

Experienced in Finance, Retail, Energy, and Agriculture domains.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Product Owner at Leading Energy & Utilities Provider (Client of Infosys), Reading, United Kingdom

December 2020 — Present

- Innovated go-to-market strategy for ~\$10 million B2B & B2C market segment; led cross-functional team of 11+ internal stakeholders to prepare new product offering.
- Established business process standardization among different workstreams and closely engaged with technology counterpart to share best practices; synchronized releases of 3 workstreams.
- Accelerated the delivery of critical capabilities in the digital transformation journey by around 20% by leading a 5 weeks engagement to set up automation test and regression suits integrated with Azure Cloud DevOps.
- Facilitated regulatory compliance implementation in the area of data privacy and data security requirement; enabling 98% in time security approvals.
- Collaborated with and stimulated the product team to create a backlog of user stories, drafting of acceptance criteria, and helped to manage the prioritization using Scrum.
- Catalogued and conducted requirement gathering workshops and further documented functional specifications.
- Reduced sign-up drop-offs from 65% to 15%, increased user-engagement by 40%, and boosted content generation by 15%, through a combination of user interviews and A/B-testing-driven product flow optimization.

Product Onwer at Market Leader in Gaming Consoles (Client of Infosys), San Diego, USA
October 2019 — November 2020

- Led a team of 2 full time employee and 3 contractors.
- Fostered open communication between executive stakeholders, engineering, and marketing, resulting in a speed improvement of the feature development lifecycle by 22 % year over year.
- Managed the elaboration of Epics, Themes, and Features into granular user stories & passed to the development teams; shaped to deliver optimum business value into a sprint cycle.
- Managed dependencies with other team's functions while identifying, building, and managing strategic partnerships across different product teams.
- Executed PI planning sessions, and other agile ceremonies for 3 scrum teams.
- Co-ordinated with POs for business case preparation and business impact assessment.
- Established 5 Key Performance Indicators (KPI), managing OKRs for synchronization with senior leadership.

Business Analyst at Leader in Consumer Goods (Client of Infosys), Germany

July 2018 — September 2019

- Devised end-to-end creative and technical design/architecture of AR/VR solutions to help appliance technicians accomplish the maintenance and routine tasks.
- Led interview campaign with existing customers (300+ person survey, 40+ face-to-face discussions) to formulate requirements of a new product to help people manage the technical issues with appliances.
- Decreased MTTR by 70% and saved 30% training man-hours; enabled improved TAC team efficiency and governance.
- Directed vendor relationship and 30% of contracts, including execution and financial payments.
- Prioritized product requirements and set realistic expectations in regards to development and timeline.
- Co-ordinated with Senior Product Manager with all tasks related to the successful launching of product at a trade show.
- Introduced a data driven project management culture by building KPI dashboard for executives around feature development and product lifecycle.

Business Analyst at World Leader in Digital Agriculture (Client of Infosys) , Indonesia April 2017 — June 2018

- Pioneered the user story acceptance criteria to get buy-in from stakeholders and refined stories with scrum teams.
- Facilitated the process of estimation of user stories, bug fixes, and spikes.
- Incorporated stakeholder feedback and persuaded other Product Owners & Managers to address concerns and identify opportunities for improvement and enhancement.
- Authored release plans and maintained a continuous release calendar.
- Collaborated with Agri-domain consultants to translate business knowledge to technical user stories.
- Created use cases and developed UML diagrams activity, sequence and class using Visio in line with product goals

EDUCATION

• Bachelors of Engineering, Panjab University, Chandigarh

CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Certified Scrum Product Owner (PSPO) I, Scrum.org

Microsoft Certified Azure Architect Expert (AZ 303, AZ 304)

IBM Certified Solution Advisor - DevOps V1

Infosys Certified Global Agile Developer

GMAT - 730 Score